As we've seen, both series and DataFrames can have indices applied to them.
如我們所見，列表(series)和DataFrames都可以應用索引(index)。
The index is essentially a row level label, and
索引本質上是行(row)的標籤，
we know that rows correspond to axis zero.
我們知道行對應於軸零(axis=0)。
In our Olympics data, we indexed the data frame by the name of the country.
在我們的奧運數據中，我們用國家的名稱對Dataframe進行索引。
Indices can either be inferred, such as when we create a new
指數可以被自動推斷，例如當我們創建新列表，
series without an index, in which case we get numeric values,
沒有指定索引時，在這種情況下，我們獲得數值索引;
or they can be set explicitly,
或者可以明確設置，
like when we use the dictionary object to create the series,
比如當我們使用字典(dictionary)創建列表時;
or when we loaded data from the CSV file and specified the header.
或者當我們下載數據時從CSV文件時,指定標頭
Another option for setting an index is to use the set_index function.
另一個選項用來設置index是使用set_index函數。
This function takes a list of columns and promotes those columns to an index.
此函數使用一個列(column)的名單，並將這些列提升為索引。
Set index is a destructive process, it doesn't keep the current index.
set_index是個破壞性過程，它不保留當前的索引。
If you want to keep the current index, you need to manually create a new column and
如果要保留當前索引，則需要手動創建一個新的列，
copy into it values from the index attribute.
並從index屬性將其複製到其中。
Let's go back to our Olympics DataFrame.
我們回到我們的奧運DataFrame。
Let's say that we don't want to index the DataFrame by countries, but
假設我們不想按照國家來索引DataFrame，
instead want to index by the number of gold medals that were won at summer games.
而是要按夏季奧運中獲得的金牌數量進行來索引。
First we need to preserve the country information into a new column.
首先，我們需要將原來的國家索引保存到新的列('country')。
We can do this using the indexing operator or the string that has the column label.
我們可以使用索引操作或具有列標籤的字串來執行此操作。
Then we can use the set_index to set index of the column to summer gold medal wins.
然後我們用set_index，使用夏季金牌獲得數量column，來設置新的索引。
You'll see that when we create a new index from an existing column it appears that
你會看到，當我們從一個現有的列創建一個新的索引時，看起來
a new first row has been added with empty values.
一個新的空行被添加在第一行。
This isn't quite what's happening.
這並不是像你看到的。
And we know this in part because an empty value is actually rendered
而我們知道這一點，部分原因是，一個空值實際上將被給予
either as a none or an NaN if the data type of the column is numeric.
none或NaN，如果列的數據類型是數值。
What's actually happened is that the index has a name.
實際發生的是索引有一個名字。
Whatever the column name was in the Jupiter notebook has just provided this
無論列名是什麼，Jupyter筆記本會提供它
in the output.
在輸出裡。
We can get rid of the index completely by calling the function reset_index.
我們可以通過調用reset_index函數完全去除索引。
This promotes the index into a column and creates a default numbered index.
這提升原來的索引成一個列，並創建內定的編號索引。
One nice feature of pandas is that it has the option to do multi-level indexing.
Pandas的一個很好的功能是可以選擇進行多層次索引。
This is similar to composite keys in relational database systems.
這與關連資料庫系統中的複合鍵類似。
To create a multi-level index, we simply call set index and
要創建多層次索引，我們只需調用set_index，
give it a list of columns that we're interested in promoting to an index.
給一個列的列表，包含我們有興趣提升為索引的。
Pandas will search through these in order, finding the distinct data and
Pandas將按順序搜索這些資料，找出不同的數據
forming composite indices.
並形成綜合索引指數。
A good example of this is often found when dealing with geographical data which
我們經常可以發現很好的例子，在處理地理數據，
is sorted by regions or demographics.
按區域或人口統計來分類的數據。
Let's change data sets and look at some census data for a better example.
我們來改數據集，查看一些普查資料，以獲得更好的例子。
This data is stored in the file census.csv and
該數據存儲在文件census.csv中，
comes from the United States Census Bureau.
來自美國人口普查局。
In particular,
尤其是尤其是
this is a breakdown of the population level data at the US county level.
這是美國縣級人口數據的詳細細節。
It's a great example of how different kinds of data sets might
這是一個很好的例子，說明不同類型的數據
be formatted when you're trying to clean them.
可能的格式，當您嘗試清理數據集時。
For instance, in this data set there are two summarized levels,
例如，在這個數據集中有兩個總結級別，
one that contains summary data for the whole country.
一個包含整個國家的摘要數據。
And one that contains summary data for each state, and
一個包含每個州的摘要數據，
one that contains summary data for each county.
一個包含每個縣的摘要數據。
I often find that I want to see a list of all the unique values in a given column.
我經常發現我想看到給定列中所有獨特值的列表。
In this DataFrame, we see that the possible values for
在這個DataFrame中，我們可以看到可能的獨特值在
the sum level are using the unique function on the DataFrame.
SUMLEV，使用unique()函數在DataFrame。
This is similar to the SQL distinct operator.
這與SQL裡distinct運算符類似。
Here we can run unique on the sum level of our current DataFrame and
在這裡，我們可以執行unique()在這個DataFrame的SUMLEV，
see that there are only two different values, 40 and 50.
看到只有兩個不同的值，即40和50.
Let's get rid of all of the rows that are summaries at the state level and
讓我們除掉每一行州的摘要數據，
just keep the county data.
只保留縣級數據。
Also while this data set is interesting for a number of different reasons,
此外，基於許多不同的原因，這數據集是很有趣味的，
let's reduce the data that we're going to look at to just the total population
讓我們將減少我們將要查看的數據，僅包括總人口
estimates and the total number of births.
估計和總出生次數。
We can do this by creating a list of column names that we want to keep
我們可以這樣做，通過創建我們想要保留的列名稱的列表，
then project those and assign the resulting DataFrame to our df variable.
然後對這列表進行投入，並將生成的DataFrame分配給我們的df變量。
The US Census data breaks down estimates of population data by state and county.
美國人口普查數據分析人口數據估計按照州和縣的方式。
We can load the data and set the index to be a combination of the state and
我們可以載入數據並將索引設置為州和
county values and see how pandas handles it in a DataFrame.
縣的組合，並查看Pandas如何在DataFrame中處理它。
We do this by creating a list of the column identifiers we want to
我們可以這樣做，通過創建列標籤的列表，我們想要用來
have indexed.
當索引的。
And then calling set index with this list and assigning the output as appropriate.
然後使用此列表，用set_index並酌情指定輸出變量。
We see here that we have a dual index, first the state name and
我們在這裡看到我們有一個雙重索引，首先是州名，
then the county name.
然後是縣名。
An immediate question which comes up is how we can query this DataFrame.
一個直接的問題是我們如何查詢這個DataFrame。
For instance, we saw previously that the loc attribute of
例如，我們以前看到loc屬性
the DataFrame can take multiple arguments.
在DataFrame可以用多個參數。
And it could query both the row and the columns.
它可以查詢行(row)和列(column)。
When you use a MultiIndex,
當您使用Multi-Index時，
you must provide the arguments in order by the level you wish to query.
您必須按照要查詢的級別順序提供參數。
Inside of the index, each column is called a level and
在索引的內部，每列稱為一個級別，
the outermost column is level zero.
最外面的列為級別零。
For instance, if we want to see the population results from Washtenaw County,
例如，如果我們想看到Washtenaw縣的人口結果，
which is where I live, you'd want to the first argument as the state of Michigan.
我住的地方，那麼你要將用第一個參數為密歇根州Michigan。
You might be interested in just comparing two counties.
你可能有興趣只比較兩個縣。
For instance, Washtenaw where I live and Wayne County which covers Detroit.
例如，我住的Washtenaw和覆蓋Detroit的Wayne縣。
To do this, we can pass the loc method,
為此，我們可以傳遞loc方法，
a list of tuples which describe the indices we wish to query.
一個的元組(tuple)列表(list)，描述我們希望查詢的索引。
Since we have a MultiIndex of two values, the state and the county,
由於我們有一個Multi-Index的兩個值，州和縣，
we need to provide two values as each element of our filtering list.
我們需要提供每個元素兩個值，作為我們的過濾列表。
Okay so that's how hierarchical indices work in a nutshell.
好的，這就是扼要的解釋層次索引。
They're a special part of the pandas library which I
他們是Pandas程式庫的一個特殊部分，
think can make management and reasoning about data easier.
我認為可以使數據的管理和推理更容易。
Of course hierarchical labeling isn't just for rows.
當然，層次標籤不僅適用於行(row)。
For example, you can transpose this matrix and now have hierarchical column labels.
例如，您可以轉置此矩陣，現在具有列(column)的層次標籤。
And projecting a single column which has these labels
投影一個具有這些標籤的列，
works exactly the way you would expect it to.
正如您所期望的方式運行。